DINESH LAMBA M.D., MPH

PROFILE

Experienced Healthcare Business Analyst and highly regarded Subject Matter Expert for strong Clinical background and applications, with 10 years of experience in the Healthcare Industry. Excellent reputation for resolving problems, improving customer/patient satisfaction, and driving overall operational improvements. Diverse and competitive portfolio, with a strong passion towards quality Healthcare and Patient care. Technical expertise include owning and operating an Independent Family Practice, serving as a Clinical instructor, conducting Clinical research studies, and implementing accountable care methods and metrics at Independent Practices and Hospitals. Positive attitude with an ability to learn, work in a challenging environment, build relationships, and become a knowledgeable. dependable, and passionate employee for the Organization.

CONTACT

PHONE: EMAIL:

904-208-8495

DRLAMBA.DINESH@GMAIL.COM

<u>Linkedln: https://www.linkedin.com/in/dinesh-lamba-7035a99/</u>

EDUCATION

<u>Doctorate in Medicine (MD)</u> University of Pune, India (1997)

Doctorate in Medicine (MD) ECFMG Certified, 2018

Master's in Public Health (MPH)
University of North Florida (2006)

<u>Post Graduate Diploma in Clinical Research</u> Kriger Research Center (2008)

Post Graduate Diploma in Business Analyst and MS-SQL

United Global Soft (2018)

SKILLS

- Proficient in Microsoft Office
- Citrix NextGen EHR, CareSentry, Optum 360 MRA
- SME in HIPPA, ICD-9 & ICD-10 codes, HCC guidelines
- Expert in guidelines for Clinical Studies

WORK EXPERIENCE

STUDENT

GEORGIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, ATLANTA, GA (JUNE 2019 – PRESENT)

- Enrolled in Data Science and Analytics Boot Camp.
- Learning use and application of tools and databases for data analytics and visualization of social, consumer, or organization trends.

STUDENT

US MEDICAL LICENSING EXAMS (USMLE) (OCTOBER 2014 – JUNE 2019)

- Invested full-time in completing five USMLE Exams in order to apply for Residency and be able to practice in the United States. Each exam requires 8-12 months of preparation.
- Successfully passed all exams in the 92nd percentile and obtained USMLE certification.
- Residency Admission not secured due to highly competitive environmental and limited acceptance of IMG applicants.

HEALTHCARE BUSINESS AND RISK ASSESSMENT ANALYST

FAMILY CARE PARTNERS, JACKSONVILLE, FL (JANUARY 2013 – Present)

- Served as the Organization's lead to implement Accountable Care Organizations' (ACO) goals and objectives and Medicare Risk Adjustment (MRA)
- Lead Medicare Risk Assessor and Healthcare Quality and Risk Analyst.
- Responsible for implementing policies and procedures related to Medicare Global Risk adjustments plans.
- Managed the Disease Management team by providing Care Management Services via Cardiocom and Dexcom.
- Served on the Utilization Management team as an SME.

MEDICARE RISK ADJUSTER; FAMILY PHYSICIANS GROUP, JACKSONVILLE, FL (OCTOBER 2009 – MARCH 2011)

- Lead Medicare Risk Assessor and Healthcare Quality and Risk Analyst.
- Responsible for accurate- reimbursements from CMS as a result of thorough documentation of risk reduction of enrolled patients and medical necessity.
- Managed the Organization's Disease Management team.

HEAD OF CLINICAL AFFAIRS AND PATIENT CARE SME

GREEN POINT TECHNOLOGY SERVICES LTD MUMBAI, INDIA JANUARY 2008 – OCTOBER 2008

- Served as the lead coordinator for pre-clinical research study screening report preparations.
- Worked with SMEs to establish the Clinical Research Unit in the Organization.

CLINICAL INSTRUCTOR

A. PHILIP RANDOLPH HIGH SCHOOL, JACKSONVILLE, FL AUGUST 2006 – SEPTEMBER 2007

MEDICAL ASSISTANT

UNIVERSITY OF NORTH FLORIDA STUDENT MEDICAL SERVICES, JACKSONVILLE, FL (AUGUST 2004 – MAY 2007)

DIRECTOR AND FAMILY CARE PHYSICIAN

INDEPENDENT FAMILY PRACTICE, MUMBAI, INDIA (JULY 1999 – AUGUST 2004)

DINESH LAMBA M.D., MPH

- Programming Languages: Python, PostgreSQL, HMTL, CSS, JavaScript, MS VBA
- Data Libraries/Technologies: Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Flask, SQLAlchemy, MySQL, MongoDB, APIs, Jupyter Notebook, Bootstrap
- Data Visualization: Tableau, D3.js, Leaflet.js, Plotly
- Machine Learning/Deep Learning in Pandas